Guide to the Office of the President Records, Alan Simpson Files, 1949-1979
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- Series IX. Special Projects and Events, 1956-1975
  - Vassar-Yale Study — Alternatives, 1966-1967 (Folder 86.17)
  - Vassar-Yale Study — Study of Other Institutions including Lieberman and Griffen Reports, 1967 (Folder 86.18)
  - Vassar-Yale Study — Comparative Data Compiled for the Two Institutions with Recommendations (Folder 86.19)
  - Yale University Departmental Reports, 1967 Sep (Folder 86.20)
  - Vassar College Departmental Reports, 1967 Sep (Folder 86.21)
  - Vassar-Yale Study — Preliminary Report from the Joint Study Committee, 1967 Sep (Folder 86.22)
  - Vassar-Yale Report from the Joint Study Committee, 1967 Sep (Folder 87.1)
  - Report on Men’s Education, 1968 May 23 (Folder 87.2)
  - Report on Men’s Education — Preliminary, 1968 May 1 (Folder 87.3)
  - Report on Men’s Education and Possible Approaches, 1968 May (Folder 87.4)
  - Record of Interviews with Consultants — Education of Men (Folder 87.5)
  - Report on Alternative from the Committee on New Dimensions, 1967 Sep 1 (Folder 87.6)
  - Vassar Institute for the Advancement of College and University Teaching — Report, 1969 May (Folder 87.7)
  - Report of the Joint Ad-Hoc Committee on the Graduate Center, 1970 Sep 9 (Folder 87.8)
- Series X. Personal, circa 1955-1977
  - Vassar College Commencement Address, 1964 May 31 (Folder 87.9)
  - President’s Remarks at Faculty Meetings, 1964-1973 (Folder 87.10)
  - “Shrinking the Shadow” — Convocation Address, 1964 Sep 16 (Folder 87.11)
  - Inaugural Address, 1964 Oct 16 (Folder 87.12)
  - President’s Charge to the Class of 1965, 1965 Jun 6 (Folder 87.13)
  - Thank You from the President — AAVC Annual Meeting, 1965 Jun 12 (Folder 87.14)
  - A Livable Environment — Remarks at Pine Manor Junior College Dedication of New Campus, 1965 Oct 27-28 (Folder 87.15)
  - Speech Folder #2, 1965-1966 (Folder 87.16)
  - President’s Remarks at Senior Convocation, 1966 May 11 (Folder 87.17)
  - New Realities in Women’s Lives (Bennett College Commencement), 1966 Jun (Folder 87.18)
  - President’s Remarks at Reunion, 1967 Jun 10 (Folder 87.19)
  - Speech Folder #3, 1966-1967 (Folder 87.20)
  - Speech Folder #4, 1967-1968 (Folder 87.21)
  - President’s Remarks — Alumnae Reunion, 1968 Jun 8 (Folder 87.22)
  - Speech Folder #5, 1968-1969 (Folder 87.23)
  - President’s Speeches including remarks at Faculty Meetings, 1970-1971 (Folder 87.24)
  - Meeting with Students in re Guidelines for Hiring and Reviewing Faculty, 1971 Apr 21 (Folder 87.25)
  - President’s Speeches including remarks at Faculty Meetings, 1971-1972 (Folder 87.26)
  - President’s Remarks to Alumnae, 1972 Jun 3 (Folder 87.27)
  - President Simpson’s Remarks at AAVC Annual Meeting, 1973 Jun 9 (Folder 87.28)
  - Installation of Katherine Michel as Chairman, American College in Jerusalem, 1973 Jun 24 (Folder 88.1)
  - Speeches and Articles, 1973-1974 (Folder 88.2)
  - Speeches — Hawaii, 1974 Jan (Folder 88.3)
  - Speeches and Articles, 1974-1975 (Folder 88.4)
  - Convocation Speech, 1974 Sep 4 (Folder 88.5)
  - Special College Convocation, 1975 Apr 16 (Folder 88.6)
  - Spring Convocation, 1975 Apr 30 (Folder 88.7)
  - Alumnae Reunion Speeches, 1975 May (Folder 88.8)
  - President’s Remarks to Faculty, 1975-1976 (Folder 88.9)
  - Speeches, 1975-1976 (Folder 88.10)
  - President’s Articles for the Miscellany News and Chronicle, 1975-1976 (Folder 88.11)
  - Speeches, 1976-1977 (Folder 88.12)
  - President’s Remarks to Faculty, 1976-1977 (Folder 88.13)
  - Webster Papers — Article, 1977 (Folder 88.14)
  - Address to Phi Beta Kappa, 1976 Apr 13 (Folder 88.15)
  - Reunion Remarks, 1976 May 22 (Folder 88.16)
  - Speeches and Articles from Simpson’s Locker, 1962-1977 (Folder 88.17)
  - Remarks at Inauguration of Leon Botstein, 1975 Oct 11 (Folder 88.18)
  - “The Fifty Years of Vassar I Have Seen”, 1976 Apr 28 (Folder 88.19)
  - Jean Webster Letters and Chapters (Folder 88.20)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1970-1971 (Folder 88.21)
  - Invitations to Speak Refused, 1971-1975 (Folder 88.22)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1970-1971 (Folder 88.23)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1969-1970 (Folder 88.24)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1968-1969 (Folder 88.25)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak. Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1967-1968 (Folder 88.26)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1969-1970 (Folder 88.27)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1968-1969 (Folder 88.28)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1967-1968 (Folder 88.29)
  - Invitations to Speak Accepted (or interviews, etc.), 1971-1973 (Folder 88.30)
  - History 236 — German History (Folder 88.31)
  - The Greek and Roman World — Greek History, 1976 (Folder 88.32)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1964-1965 (Folder 88.33)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1965-1966 (Folder 88.34)
  - Invitations Accepted to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1966-1967 (Folder 88.35)
  - Storm King — Speech, 1967 (Folder 89.1)
  - Interviews Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1964-1965 (Folder 89.2)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1965-1966 (Folder 89.3)
  - Invitations Refused to Speak, Give Interviews, Write Articles, 1966-1967 (Folder 89.4)
  - Vassar — Invitations to Speak, Give Interviews, Etc., 1963-1964 (Folder 89.5)
  - Invitations — Speaking, Lecturing, Writing Reviews, Etc., 1961-1964 (Folder 89.6)
  - Alan Simpson Speaking Engagements, Etc., 1960-1964 (Folder 89.7)
  - Research materials (Thomas Cullum), approximately 1955-1960 (Folder 89.7b-c)
  - Research materials, approximately 1955-1960; (microfilm images) (Folder 89.7d)
- Series XI. Additions, circa 1958-1979
  - College Architects (Carlhian), 1975 (Folder 89.8)
  - College Center, 1970-1976 (Folder 89.9)
  - Faculty Housing: Carriage Hill, 1973 (Folder 89.10)
  - Vassar Farm: Guidelines for Study, 1975 (Folder 89.11)
  - Farm, 1970-1973 (Folder 89.12)
  - Farm Study, 1973-1974 (Folder 89.13)
  - Marion Becker’s Material in re Farm Study, 1970-1976 (Folder 89.14)
  - Vassar Farm — Nature Center Proposal (Folder 89.15)
  - Griffin House (Warthin), 1964 (Folder 89.16)
  - Leslie Koempel House, 1972 (Folder 89.17)
  - Kendrick House, 1975 (Folder 89.18)
  - Library Planning, 1972-1973 (Folder 89.19)
  - Library — Proposed Expansion, 1972-1973 (Folder 89.20)
  - Howe Report — Salaries, Tenure, and Financing, 1963 (Folder 89.21)
  - Miscellaneous Documents Misfiled with Speeches, 1973-1977 (Folder 89.22)
  - Recommendations, 1962-1969 (Folder 89.23)
  - Recommendations, 1959-1964 (Folder 89.24)
  - Vassar College Bulletin — Report of Officers Issue, 1958 Jul – Dec 1962 (Folder 90.1)
  - Presidential Evaluation — Assessment of Institutional Leadership, 1976 Mar (Folder 90.2)
  - Joint Trustee-Administration-Faculty Committee, 1963 (Folder 90.3)
  - The River Course, 1965-1966 (Folder 90.4)
  - Expansion of Field Work Office — Proposal, 1962 (Folder 90.5)
  - Yearbook Controversy — Letters and Articles re, 1975 (Folder 90.6)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Task Force, 1973 (Folder 90.7)
  - Trustee-Administration Committee to study Faculty Salaries, Promotions, etc., 1963 (Folder 90.8)
  - Cross Reference — New Folder — Open File, 1965-1975 (Folder 90.9)
  - Senior Staff Meetings — Minutes, 1976-1977 (Folder 90.10)
  - Joint Committee, 1963 (Folder 90.11)
  - Report on the Education of Minority Students, 1970 Nov 6 (Folder 90.12)
  - Material For Storeroom (Miscellaneous Documents), 1968-1969, 1978 (Folder 90.13)
  - Commencement, 1967-1968 (Folder 90.14)
  - Trustee Reports, 1975-1976 (Folder 90.15)
  - An “Engineering” Education for Mid-Hudson, 1970 Apr (Folder 90.16)
  - Faculty Evaluation, 1971-1972 (Folder 90.17)
  - Commencement, 1965-1966 (Folder 90.18)
  - Trustees — C, 1976 (Folder 90.19)
  - Trustees — E, 1977 (Folder 90.20)
  - Frances T. Farenthold, 1976 (Folder 90.21)
  - Trustees — H, 1976-1977 (Folder 90.22)
  - Trustees — J, 1976 (Folder 90.23)
  - Trustees — O, 1976-1977 (Folder 90.24)
  - Trustees — T, 1976-1977 (Folder 90.25)
  - Trustees — V, 1976-1977 (Folder 90.26)
  - Faculty Salary Evaluations — Book I, 1976 (Folder 90.27)
  - Faculty Salary Evaluations — Book II, 1976 (Folder 90.28)
  - Miscellaneous Unfiled Documents, 1969-1979 (Folder 90.29)
  - Report: "The Experience of Campus-Wide Governance Arrangements at Vassar College," prepared by M. Glen Johnson, 1975 Dec (Folder 90.30)
  - Inauguration scrapbook, 1964 Oct 16 (Box 91)
  - Research materials, approximately 1955-1960; (microfilm) (Boxes 92-93)
  - Research materials (Cornwallis, Gordon Lee Goodman, Townsend Accounts, Thomas Cullum, Ipswich), circa 1958 (Box 94)
  - Inaugural salutation from Birmingham University, 1964 (Map Case - Drawer 29)